<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jaantuska-todobaadka on Abdimalik</title>
    <link>/tags/jaantuska-todobaadka/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jaantuska-todobaadka on Abdimalik</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 10:25:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/jaantuska-todobaadka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Somalia: Centralized High School Exams Taking Hold</title>
      <link>/somalia-centralized-high-school-exams-taking-hold/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 10:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/somalia-centralized-high-school-exams-taking-hold/</guid>
      <description>Private education networks were formed by local business leaders to fill the void left by the government. Over time, the networks created a cartel-like chokehold over the entire education system. They resisted any form of regulatory supervision or reform. Each network operated its own set of scattered, incoherent and low quality curriculums, resulting in the proliferation of substandard examinations and certifications.
Progress: Centralized Examinations Taking Hold
Despite the well entrenched vested opposition; gov’t led exams were since then, not only held successfully each year, each year had also registered a record growth in the number of candidates, schools, districts and regions joining the national examination system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kalawareeg: Mapping Police Violence Against Bajaaj Drivers in Mogadishu</title>
      <link>/kalawareeg-mapping-police-violence-against-motorists-in-somalia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 05:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kalawareeg-mapping-police-violence-against-motorists-in-somalia/</guid>
      <description>Nearly a month ago, I shared on Twitter, a new side initiative: #KalaWareeg – a citizen curated victim level database on police violence against motorists, passengers and pedestrians in Mogadishu. This was in response to unremitting spike in police misconduct, violence and killings of Bajaaj (auto-rickshaw) drivers at the many security checkpoints in the city, aptly named Kala Wareeg by residents.
As a result, the first version is now up and running on Google sheets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nearly 4000 Killed, Wounded By Suicide Attacks in Mogadishu since 2012</title>
      <link>/nearly-4000-killed-wounded-by-suicide-attacks-in-mogadishu-since-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 06:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nearly-4000-killed-wounded-by-suicide-attacks-in-mogadishu-since-2012/</guid>
      <description>Last week, Al Shabaab terrorists targeted a bustling street full of restaurants, cafes and shops near Mogadishu’s Maka Al Mukarama Hotel with twin suicide car bombs as residents enjoyed their evening with friends and family. The attack was devastating. Twenty-five people were killed, more than 130 others injured, while dozens of shops, cafeterias, and vehicles were reduced to rubble.
According to my analysis of 114 suicide bombings in the capital since 2012, suicide attacks are becoming more frequent, more complex and more lethal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Owns Somalia’s External Debt?</title>
      <link>/who-owns-somalias-external-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 20:31:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/who-owns-somalias-external-debt/</guid>
      <description>Somalia’s external debt belongs to 27 known creditors comprised of three categories: Paris Club bilateral debt ($2.5 billion, 54%), non-Paris Club bilateral creditors ($600 million, 13%) and international financial institutions such as World Bank, IMF and others ($1.5 billion, 33%). </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Somalia Prime Ministers Turn Over</title>
      <link>/somalia-prime-ministers-turn-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 20:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/somalia-prime-ministers-turn-over/</guid>
      <description>Since the rebirth of the Somali government in Djibouti in late 2000, Somalia’s progress in building viable state institutions were in large part obstructed by frequent political infighting resulting in political instabilities and a series of failed governments. During these tumultuous period, five successive Somali governments churned out sixteen prime ministers: 12 voted in by parliament, and 4 appointed to serve in interim capacities.
In February, 2017, when former prime minister Mohamed Abdullah Mohamed (Farmaajo) – who has suffered the shortest stint and a bitter ouster – was elected Somali president, he vowed to end the country’s destabilizing political culture, ones and for all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>